<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-emma-goldman</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020274/1901-09-08/ed-1/seq-29/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>It
          made me morose and envious, but 'what
          Btarted the craze to kill was a lecture I
          heard some little time ago by Emma Gold
          man. She was In Cleveland and .1 and
          other anarchists went to hear -her," She
          set me on Are,
          "Her doctrine that all rulers should be,
          exterminated was what set me to thinking,
          so that my head nearly split with the pain,
          lilss Goldman's words went right through
          me, and when I left the lecture I. had made
          up my mind that I would have to do some
          thing heroic for the cause I loved.
          resolution to shoot tub
          president formed tuesday. Yesterday morning I went again to tie
          Exposition grounds. Emma Goldman's
          speech still burning, me up. I waited near
          the central entrance for the President,
          who was to board his. special train from
          that gate, but the police allowed nobody
          but the President's party to pass where the
          train waited, so'I stayed at the grounds all
          day waiting.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1901-09-09/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Anarchist leader whoso wiltlnsj and epteches Inspired Czolgosz her fricni hnd
          companion to try to nurdcr Prrsl i dent McKluloy In being tcarched for bj the police cry
          city In the United I States The womin was with the wouldbe m anazsln In this city on
          Monday She went from here to fUtsburg thc to Cincinnati and from there toL Louis The
          police believe that ehewaa1IrsUT Involved In the plot to kill he PrestJent They are
          positive that she TSS the friend and confidant of Czolfou and wa airare of his
          determlnntlcn to aj caulnato Mr UcKlnley T6 United State Serrtee holds the theory that abs
          ma the prime mover In a widespread conspiracy which contemplated a series of crimes of
          wilo the murder of the President wu only the beginning When the woman If caucnt uolrss the
          Itw can send her to Jail the will be expelled It zcuse can be found for such procedure
          Secretaries Host and Knox held 1 I enfftny coaf erenc list ulgat and 3 edd d I to wa
          OAwarot rtcrrolnatlon on An arChlaU Orders were Issued today it U said to the Secret
          Bervlco to bold very known Anarchist In the country under nrvtinance If they voice sjrm
          hpath7 for Cxolgoaz their arrest Kill fol J Low on the round thai they are con U eptrtwr
          against the constituted minor ity and sov rnmeat of the United ite 7ttA QoMaaan with
          Cioltross bn tbo nlrht Ciotcais arrived In Duf fsjo Emma Goldman waa seen walking t 1th
          h1m on FlUmor avenue She was I 1093 with him a number of times after trfat always at night
          In the neighbor I njod of NowakV Hotel at No JOT Broadway where Csalgoti stayed On the
          night before President McKlnley arrived in the city they were together The police have not
          yet ascertained t where she stopped while in the city The part of the city in which Nowdkj
          Hotel Is situated Is thickly populated with Poles and men of anarchistic and 1 ioclallitl
          tendencies These people are not friendly with the police and In 4 formation Is obtained
          from them with great dlfllculty fly rigorous methods however the Information that Emma
          Goldman wai in the city and was with Czolgcrjz has L been wrung from the Poles Every
          person peced of knowing anything t f about tho prisoner or his woman com o s panion has
          been arrested Every hour i 3Qiucl3 of east side men and women nro brought Into Police
          Headquarters r and subjected to searching examinations < The knowledge that Czolgosza com
            panion way Emma Goldman chN the
            j pollco an Important clue She Is so
            well known In all parts the country
            that there will be little difficulty It 1> believed In bringing about
          her arrest It will not bo difficult either to ascer tain the whereabouts of aomo of her
          fellowAnarchlHts may have been Implicated In the plot Every detective In every city where
          in anarchistic or socialistic organiza tion In known to exist Is working to unearth
          evidence that may reveal the Identity of tho leaders In the plot That CznIgoaz was merely
          un Instrument the police are convinced The police here have secured records i of the
          movements of Emma Goldman sInce July U when she left Chicago to o to Rochester Her parent
          live In that city at oIn Joseph street and she Is well known there Her sister has admitted
          that sse remained there 1 until two weeks ago She is believed to have cOne from there to
          Buffalo where ei remained until after the ar rive CxolgMZ After the plot to kfll the
          President was perfected ehe went toPltt bur Then she went to Cincinnati and Bt</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020274/1901-09-09/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Kmma Goldman, the nnarchlat lecturer
          and author, who wrote the book that Czol
          gosz says' inspired him to attempt to assas
          sinate President JIcKinlcy at lluffalo. ar
          rived in Ft. Louis Thursday night. She Is
          aIdto have been In Buffalo on "Monday
          last.
          She was in this city oil day Friday, the
          day the President was fchot. hhe Mopped
          at No. '1331 South Thirteenth street, where,
          she occuple'd a room until 7 o'clacJ: Satur
          day evening. The police believe she depart
          ed later the same evening for Chicago or
          ButTalo..
          A .woman of her detcrirtlon bought ah
          order for- a. ticket to Chicago at Olliler
          sleeve's ticket oflioe, opposite Union Sta
          tion, early that evening, but subsequently
          the ticket was sold to another person.
          Whether he left the city or not,- the po
          lice and the Federal officers are making
          every effort to apprehend her. Rn order for
          her omrt having been Issued by tho CJov
          ernmeat. Detectives are working on several clews,
          the nature of. which they will not give out.,
          and the Federal authorities are slvlns the
          local' officers every aid. while thoroughly
          prosecuting .the search themselves.
          Kmma Goldman had a friend In St. Louis
          whoso name the police say Is Carl Dold.
          but who was also known .as Carl Norman.
          He was local agent for an anarchistic paper
          published In Chicago. "While in. St. Louis
          he roomed ut No. 1351 South Thirteenth
          street", a house kept .by Sirs. Emma Rager.
          The police say Dold brought Emmai- Gold
          man there two- months ago, but' say they
          do not know where from". She occupied
          Dold's" former room when here Friday.
          DoM left St Louis In July for Pittsburg,
          where he Is said to be now. It, Is also sus
          pected that, ho probably came to St Louis"
          with Emma Goldman Friday.
          The female anarchist is known to have
          been with Dold in Pittsburg, a few days
          ago. She lert there to go to ' Cincinnati.
          She was there a short while and then came
          to- St Louis, arriving Thursday night nnd
          going Immediately to Dold's former room.
          ANARCHISTS DENT THAT
          SHE IS III THE CITT. .. j</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1901-09-10/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Vc have arrcsTcdEmiim Goldman on tlic charge J of conspfc 1
          aiy to murder the Prcsidentof the United Stale 1 Jt
          Her arrest will lend to the breaking tip of the mo3tlobt o jli
          thirsty andninrdcrpti gang oft Anarchists that Imvejqvcnjnfcato r1l
          any country nF
          She sullenly ipfticc to niuke uny stutcmont butw 1 bc1ic Rf
          many others wore implicated in lie plot TheWormjjUqnilcjidin t r f r
          iti her arrest came from a private source Thief of Eolico ONcil
          Pliieugo longdistance telephone to The Evening World 1i1 I

          The warrant which Mice Goldman i arrested gives as nc f
          rocoiispirators Abraham Isaaks Maurice Isaihs Clemcnce Pfcir ij
          7cr Hipjwitc Havel Henry Travaglio Alfred Schneider Tttli I
          Mrthame Marie Ihauks and larieIrfaaks jr All but MisslGoK l I
          man were arrcstcd ome days ago Mrs Xoriib the womntHvil
          whom Mis Goldman boarded wiu arrested this afternoon 8t
          lIfc</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87075213/1901-09-11/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Emma Gold
          man, the "Anarchist Queen," undoi
          whose red banner Czolgosz clilms ho
          stands, whoso words he claims fired his
          heart and brain to attempt the assas
          sination of President McKinley, was
          arrested here shortly before noon to
          day. She disclaimed all but the slightest
          acquaintance with the President's as
          sistant. She denied absolutely thatshe
          or any anarchist phe knew was Impli
          cated in any plot to kill tho President.
          She said she believed that Czolgosz
          acted entirely on his own responsibility
          and that ho never claimed to have
          been Inspired by her ns he is quoted as
          affirming. Tho President, she averred,
          with a yawn wns an insignificant be;
          ing to her, a more human atom whose
          life or death was n matter of sum erne
          indifference to her or to any other
          anarchist.
          Czogosz act was foolish, yet, she de
          clared, it probably had Its inspiration
          In the misery which the Pole had seen
          about him. Violence, she said, Is not
          a tenet in the faith of the anarchist,,
          and she had not advocated It In Cleve
          land where Czolgosz said he heard her,
          nor clsewhcie.
          Miss Goldman anlved heic Sunday
          morning from St. Louis Sho told amid
          laughter of her captuie today. In her
          convcisation only once did she break
          down completely. That was when
          Captain Schuettler led her fiom the of
          fice of Chief of Police O'Neill tothe cab
          waiting to convey her to the woman's
          annex at the Harrison stieet police
          station. For n moment sho cried, but
          tho next moment this condition of dis
          tress was over. She said her purpose
          in coming here had been to help three
          anaichists arrested here seveial days
          ago. Sho Intended to give herself up
          to the police but delayed it until the
          polce had taken tho matter In their
          own hands. She is held on a warrant
          sworn out by Captain Colleraln, charg
          ing her- with conspiracy to murder tho
          President. As her co-conspirators aro
          named the anarchists already in jail
          here. She will bo taken befoio a mag
          Istrato tomorrow. It Is expected tha'
          the city will ask for a continuance of
          tho case pending advices fiom Buffalo.
          "I shall insist upon an Immediate
          hearing," sho Baid. "They want mo
          to go to New York without requisition
          papers, but I will not go. I know legal
          ropes, I'l mako them fight every step,
          and I'm not afraid nt that."
          A message from Chief Bull, of Buffalo
          asserts that Czolgosz was In Chicago
          August 18 in company with Emmu
          Goldman and Abraham Isaaks. Is
          aacks ond Miss Goldman claim that
          thoy took in tiying to envoi vo an nn
          C J. Norrls, at whoso homo Miss Gold
          man wns captured, was arrested later.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1901-09-11/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Chargrd with conspiracy to murder President and therefore ho desired that she be hell
          nlthout ball Mlf Goldman was not represented by counsel but expressed her dcslio to have
          an Immediate hearing With u I determined little snap of her teeth she raid she wn ready to
          proceed nlthout counsel Whvn the Court granted the contlmi ncr she said she wnnted to be
          allowed her freedom urdcr band The Magis trate said that an tho latest bulletin Indicated
          that the distinguished patient nt Uu < < ali nas on the high road to re
            covery ho would consider the matter
            of ball further and wcuM announce llj
            ckiUlon later
            linen> In Court i II Goldman appeared In court at 1
          93 e cok under the escort of Matron J Kcesan She seemed surprised that no i lawyer
          ultherclo take up her de fense and glanced uneasily about the ice in tullotuncoulh
          prisoners and curlaus spectators She asked for Invvycra Saltlcl And Hrowne They ncro not
          In court and Justice Prlndtvll said he would wait a reasonable time for them lo appear
          Although tho telephone nas kept busy > an hour clapatj and the lawyer ncrc elll ntncnt
          Chief of Detectives Collemn then d nrnilLil that the hearing should pro red U took onl a
          few minute and i jen Mils Goldman was led bach It her nm In tho womens annex She looked c1
          and nervous When Prosecutor f vena repeated the charge against her c fliiitd and then
          rmllcd 1 isked the Chief nf Police last nght t b have ljvycr HitKl lent to me he said
          IKfore leaving the courtroom 1IIIc5a ho must have forgotten It 1 l Tfxpccted that my
          friends would have jecn busy In my behalf forcflnv that niost of thtm havo been locked up
          In the mtioiiwMo dragncl which the polloe favo flung out Attorney Saltlel appeared before
          Judg i Chetlaln Just before noon today and asked permission lo rile a petition In habeas
          corpus proceedings In behalf of the Isaaks and other alleged Anarchists charged with
          having conspired with j CzolKOz for the murder of President ftlcKlnley Saltlel nnd failed
          lo notlfv Chief ONrtll Sheriff Magerstidt and Justice l Prlndlvllle nhoii the nrlt fUII
          dlrecied and Judge Chetlnln ordered him to do beforo proceeJItgs could l taken llMlinm Cor
          pun feir llpr Shortly after Mlfs Goldman left court inwjer Itrovvne calleJ on the prisoner
          nml Informed her that he will ask for n writ of habeas corpus In tier bolnlf this
          nfternnon Justice Prindlvlllc therefore rorMnted to a further postponement of the ball
          matter until 3 P M When the defendant nas c hick to the courtroom JUke Prlndl vllle nnlJ
          to her Your lawyers do not Mem to be In clined to come1 IIBSGoltlmanl learn that they nrr
          very busy nllh the other caiwa m wo nlll leave It It doesnt matter I cnn toKc charge of
          the cnse myself Prosecutor Owens I renew my motion to continue the case until Sept 17 and
          that she be held without ball ML s Goldman demanded n hearing and eked that site admitted
          to ball</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1901-09-11/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Czolgosz "called
          : at- the j Isaak • horn e and ". talked
          with Emma Goldman and > with
          Abraham; Isaak. TheV interview
          Avas renewed the following u^ay.
          Emma ' Goldman, Czolgosz
          and Abraham Isaak, and Marie
          Isaak, Vvere" in consultation in
          Chicago oh two .occasions. Ma
          rie' ' Isaak* accompanied * Emma
          Goldman to Buffalo the last time
          the; archleader . of the anarchists
          was , here. Leon Czolgosz was
          accompanied ' to Buffalo ; and
          about the city- by a mysterious
          •Bohemian, man and woman, who
          a£ted so suspiciously: as to .war
          rant "ftlie assumption . that ; they
          knew of the intention ' of CzoK
          gbsz ..to ? assassinate the Presi
          dent.' -These 'two. Bohemians, are
          now .beiiig looked for all over the
          United States. • ' ¦' . '.'.'¦.
          it can be sdid ? that during. the last
          ten weeks, Emma Gol/man has
          visited each one of the sik anar
          chist organizations'
          She : lias been iiv Buffalo \|iree
          times since July .12, having left
          the city the last time four days
          before the . attempted' .assassina
          tion.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1901-09-12/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Have extradition papers for Emma Goldman been prepared
          It was the intention of DistrictAttorney Penney to prepare
          such papers and I suppose he hns done so Thnt part of the case is
          entirely in his hands
          Will any of the other prisoners held by the Chicago police be
          extradited V
          Not at present at any rate What may be done with them
          in tho future has not been decided upon
          Have you any evidence connecting them with the assault on
          the President
          We have not but I suppose the Chicago police have We
          shall depend upon them for evidence
          What evidence have you against Emma Goldman 1</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059523/1901-09-24/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Emma Goldman Will Undoubtedly.
          ■f. :. Be Ordered Released on ; Hear- v,.
          ing- Today .Before Magis
          trate Prindiville.
          \ CHICAGO, Sept. 23.— nine ' anar-;
          chists , who have , been \ v nuer rest - here ?
          since the assassination of President Mc-
          Kinley were today given their freedom, .
          Judge :.Chetlain so; ordering after the
          prosecution had admitted that there was *
          no legal evidence against them. Emma :
          Goldman was , not . a party to the pro
          ceedings. Her case is? set for hearing
          tomorrow before ? Magistrate Prindiville,'
          where she, as well as the nine men
          freed today, is charged with .conspiracy
          to murder President McKinley; .The cages
          in the lower court with reference to -ho
          men are of course nullified by t._e action
          of Judge Chetlain today. Miss Goldman
          will also be set at liberty, as Justice
          Prindiville has agreed to. take such ac
          tion in her case as the upper court took
          in the cases of the men. Attorney Brown
          said he would like to have Miss Goldman
          freed today. . When the. hearing;on the
          writ of habeas corpus began.before Judge
          Chetlain, .Dr. Taylor, the city prosecu
          tor, arose and at once declared that he
          could no longer ask that the prisoners be
          held. -
          "We have no legal evidence against
          them,", he said. "They were' arrestee! at.
          the request of the Buffalo authorities,
          and since their incarceration we have
          been in constant touch with the Eastern
          police. I was informed this morning
          that Chief Beall had no evidence against
          them and I -..ve also been informed that
          there is no Intention of trying to extra
          dite them. We are therefore willing that
          the relators be freed;"
          Attorney Geeting, the relators, then
          demanded that in view of the gravity of
          the offense, which.had been charged
          asainst his clients that the prosecution
          be required to state.what cause, or what
          suspicions, weighed with the police -in
          making the arrest.
          Judge Chetlain said that in view of the
          fact that the prosecution representing
          both the city and the state, a* well as
          Buffalo by indirection, had agree- to the
          liberation of the prisoners* and admitted
          that there was no evidence against them;
          that there was no reason for further in
          quiry into the matter.
          "When arrested the charge against the
          relators was merely a misdemeanor and
          they were entitled to bail," the court
          said. "The case was one of such moment,
          however, and the whole nation was de
          manding of its officers their best efforts,
          that I felt justified in exercising all dis
          cretion. The prisoners, were therefore
          remanded without bail for further hear
          ing, pending an investigation by the
          police. The president died from the as
          sassin's bullet and the prisoners this
          time were remanded without bail at their
          own request to allow the fullest investi
          gation. Our duty has been fully done
          and now we have but to order and do so
          order, that the prisoners be liberated "
          The prisoners had been silent, their
          faces expressionless during the proceed
          ings. When the court ordered the jail
          doors opened to them there was not a
          trace of rejoicing on their faces.*
          The prisoners were led back to jail
          where they collected their belongings
          and then came down stairs, where they
          met friends and men of their faith. For
          the first time they showed evidences of
          pleasure. Capt. Rever, of the police de
          partment, offered them protection on the
          way to their homes., but Abraham
          .Frank, the editor, of an anarchist paper
          and looked upon as j the leader of local
          anarchists," refused It.. The party then
          aeparted in various directions.
          Emma Goldman,received the news of
          the liberation of her friends with a laugh.
          "I guess they'll have to let me go
          now," she said. "It has been shown
          that the men namcjl as conspirators with
          me did not conspire; and I fancy they
          would have trouble trying to show that I
          conspired all by myself." ' ' "*
          Assistant City Prosecutor Owen was
          asked by counsel for Miss Goldman to
          bring Miss Goldman's case before Justice
          Prindiville this afternoon that the de
          fendant might be free tonight. He said
          he would consider the matter.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84028140/1901-09-24/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Emma Goldman
          Is Free.
          Chicago, Sept. 24.-(Spl.)-Emnia
          Goldman Is again a free woman, tho
          charge of conspiracy to asasslnate
          tho President, having been iIIsiiiIhsocI
          this morning at the request of the
          City Prosecutor, who Informed tho
          court that tho prosecuting attorney
          at Buffalo had notified him that there
          .was no evidence tgaliwt her.
          The court room was packed If suf
          focation when the "high prlostos of
          anarchy" was brought In, the great
          majority of tho spectator being an
          urchists. There vuis no attempt at ft
          demonstration until court adjourned,
          when the nuarchlsts crowded around
          their leader, men and women ombnie
          Ing and kissing her.
          She immediately started for the
          home of the Isanks, where a banquet
          Iti honor of all the released anarchists
          was given. A great crowd followed
          her, ome cheering, other leering.
          She boie heiself proudly and sueered
          at those who jeered her and bulled
          pleasantly at those who cheered.
          Miss Coldman will lenialu In Chi
          cago several days, delivering lectures.
          Then she will go to New York.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020274/1901-09-24/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The 'nine anarchists
          who have' been under -arrest hero since the
          assassination of President McKinley to-day
          got their freedom. Judge Shetlaln so order
          ing, after the prosecution had admitted that,
          there was no legal evidence, against them.
          Emma. Goldman .was not a party to the
          proceedings. Her case Is. set for hearing. UH
          morrow, before Magistrate PrlndivlUe, where
          -she,, as well as. the nine -men freed to-day,
          is cnargea wiui conspiracy tu "uu
          President McKinley. The eases in the lower
          court with reference . to. the ..men is. of
          course.-' nullified, by -the action . of Judge
          Chetlaln to-day. Miss Goldman will also be
          set at liberty, as Justice '.Prindtvllie-naS
          agreed' to take such action. in" her case as
          e upper court took." in the cases of tne
          men.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1901-09-24/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text> Emma
          Goldman.was not a "party to the proceed
          ings. Her case is set for hearing to-mor
          row before Magistrate Prindlville. where
          she, as well- as the nine men freed to
          day, are charged with conspiracy to mur
          der President McKinley. The cases in the
          lower court with reference to the men are
          of course, nullified hy the action of Judge
          Chetlaln to-day. . Miss . Goldman will alsj
          be. set af liberty, as Justice Prlndiville
          has agreed to take such action in her
          case as the. upper court took:in ; the cases
          of * the men. Attorney:; Brown ' said he
          would try. to' have. Miss. Goldman freed
          to-day. ' When the court ordered the lib
          eration of theprisoners .there was not a
          trace of jubilation in their; faces. Thev
          snt silent and their faces expressionless.
          Emma Goiuman received. the news of
          the liberation of her friends with a laugh.
          "I guess. they'll have. to let me go now,"
          she said. . -"It --has been shown' that ~\ the
          men named as conspirators' with, me did
          not. conspire, and. I fancy they would
          have trouble trying to show I conspired
          all by myself."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1913-06-10/ed-1/seq-28/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1910-09-29/ed-1/seq-12/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1906-09-22/ed-1/seq-28/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>After the assassination of President McKinley
          an attempt was made to arrange
          some agreement among the nations of the
          world to stamp out the anarchists. There
          was a great deal of correspondence between
          the diplomatists and there seemed
          to be a general disposition to make a uniform
          treaty to exp^l and to refuse admission
          to all professional anarchists, nihilists
          and others who advocate assassination
          as a political measure and are opposed
          to law and order. The Congress of the
          United States passed a law on the subject
          and stiffened the regulations of the immigration
          bureau, but nothing further was
          done about the matter.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014086/1914-08-29/ed-1/seq-13/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84036276/1901-09-13/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>So far as he can be learned Czolgoz has
          'refused to mention any name except that
          of Emma Goldman, but papers are in
          existence which, if they can be discov
          ered, will lay bare the entire conspiracy
          -and will result in wholesale arrests, fol
          lowed by prosecutions.
          In his confession Czolgosz has told of
          his attempt to destroy the written evi
          dence of the conspiracy. He said that
          time did not permit him to burn the
          papers, as he had desired. Czolgoesz says
          that if he was to meet the president at
          the Temple of Muses at the pan-Ameri
          can exposition he had to be there early.
          Before leaving his room in Novak's ho
          EMMA GOLDMAN, FEMALE ANARCHIST,
          ARRESTED AT HOME OF A CHICAGO FRIEND
          CHICAGo, Sept. 11.-Emma Goldman,
          who was arrested by the Chicago police
          yesterday told the chief that she was
          having a little fun at the expense of the
          police department." She had intended
          today to give herself up to the police.
          "If these officers had come twenty min
          utes later I would not have been there,"
          she said. I would have been on my way
          to deliver myself to the police."
          An emphatic denial met the sugges
          tion that the assassin was spurred to his
          deed by her utterances.
          "I dont believe it," she cried, earnest
          ly. "I don't believe he ever said it. I
          have read the accounts, but I don't be
          Slieve they are true. I never urged vio
          lence. My lectures have never been
          published in a pamphlet or in a book.
          They have been printed in periodicals,
          but they never have been printed in per
          riodicals, but they never have advocated
          murder. I do not favor such means to
          our end."
          Miss Goldman wears heavy gold-rim
          med eye glasses, with powerful lenses.
          A prominent lower jaw, protruding
          slightly, gives evidence of determination
          which might escape notice at a casual
          glance. Her light hair, almost red, was
          brushed back from a broad forehead.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84022060/1898-04-23/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83016689/1912-11-02/ed-1/seq-12/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83016758/1901-09-12/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>I there ev er was an accomplice to a
          crime it is Emma Goldman, whose
          writings and talks sent the assassin's
          bullets into President McKinley's body.
          She should be summarily dealt with.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86069457/1901-09-12/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Leon Czolgosz the
          accused and self confessed assassin
          has signed a confession covering si
          pages of foolscap and which states
          that he is an anarchist and that ho
          became an enthusiastic member of
          that body through the influence of
          Emma Goldman whoso writings ho
          had read and whose lectures he had
          listened to He denies having any
          confederate and says he decided on
          the act three days ago and bought tho
          revolver with which the crime was
          committed in Buffalo He has seven
          brothers and sisters in Cleveland anil
          the Cleveland directory has the names
          of about that number living on Hos
          mer street and Ackland avenue which
          adjoin Some of them are butchers
          and others are employed in different
          trades He is now detained at pollco
          headquarters pending the result of
          the presidents injuries
          Czolgosz does not appear in the
          least degree uneasy or penitent for
          his action He says he was induced
          by his attention to Emma Goldmans
          lectures und writings to decide that
          the present form of government in
          this country was all wrong and ho
          thought the best way to end it was
          by killing the president He shows no
          sign of insanity but is very reticent
          about much of his career While ac
          knowledging himself an anarchist he
          does not state to what branch of the
          organization he belongs</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88064454/1901-09-14/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>